Encounters are mysterious! But the world is even more so!
لقاءات البشر مغلّفة بالغموض، والعالم تلفّه طبقات أكثر حتّى
I'm so glad I'm with you!
!أنا مسرورٌ حقّاً لكوني معك
Great detective work is on today's menu! Eat up and solve the case!
!عمل تحرٍّ بارع على قائمة اليوم! كُل وحلّ القضيّة
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
During a sudden blackout at Ran's cooking class,
،أثناء انقطاع تيّار مفاجئ في فصل طهو ران
the teacher, Uemori Michi, was stabbed in the back and killed!
طُعنت المعلّمة، أويموري ميتشي، في ظهرها من قِبل شخصٍ ما وقُتلت
String and ice had been used to turn off the electrical room breaker.
استعمل الفاعل خيطاً وقالباً جليدياً لإنزال القاطع في غرفة المفاتيح
And, after investigation, the possibility of an outside killer vanished!
وبعد التحرّي، زالت احتماليّة !كون القاتل من الخارج
All four of you could have set up the ice trick in the electrical room.
كان بإمكان أيٍّ منكم أنتم الأربعة إعداد حيلة القالب الجليديّ في غرفة المفاتيح
There's a refrigerator here,
توجد ثلّاجة هنا
and the ice could've been brought from home.
وكان بإمكانكم جلب الجليد من منازلكم
Meaning the murder weapon is the issue.
ما يعني أنّ سلاح الجريمة هو المشكلة هنا
Yes...
أجل
Yuko-san. Are there any ice picks in this classroom?
يوكو-سان، أتوجد كسّارات ثلج في هذا الفصل؟
Yes. In the bottom drawer, next to the microwave oven.
أجل، في الدرج السفليّ بجوار المايكرويف
Inspector. These iron skewers have sharp tips.
حضرة المفتّش، لهذه الأسياخ الحديديّة رؤوس حادّة
Yuko-san. Do you keep count of how many there are?
يوكو-سان، أتقومين بعدّها دوماً؟
Yes. There should be ten.
أجل، يُفترض أنّها عشرة
There are only nine here.
توجد تسعة فقط
That can't be! There were ten when I counted last night!
!مستحيل! كانت عشرةً عندما عددتُ البارحة
Inspector! We have our murder weapon!
!حضرة المفتّش! هذا هو سلاح الجريمة
The killer stole a skewer from that drawer in advance
سرق المجرم سيخاً من الدرج سلفاً
and used it to stab Uemori-san!
!وطعن به أويموري-سان
But could you really stab with this? There's nowhere to grip it.
لكن أيمكنك طعن شخص بهذا؟ لا ممسك له
If it were me, I'd choose something with a handle.
كنتُ لأختار أداةً بمقبض لو كنت مكانه
Plus, the mark on her back seemed smaller than those skewers' tips.
كما أنّ الأثر على ظهرها بدا أصغر من رؤوس هذه السياخ
Inspector. We should check their belongings.
حضرة المفتّش، علينا تفقّد ممتلكاتهم الشخصيّة
Yeah.
معك حقّ
Okay, everyone. Please place all your belongings on the table.
إذاً يا سادة، ضعوا كلّ ممتلكاتكم الشخصيّة على الطاولة رجاءً
Everyone has aprons, pens, handkerchiefs, and recipes...
...يملك الجميع مرايلاً وأقلام حبر ومحارماً ووصفات
I don't see the skewer anywhere.
لا يبدو أنّ السيخ موجود
Oh? Only Kazue-san has a notebook and a brush.
ماذا؟ أنتِ وحدك يا كازوي-سان من لديها مذكّرة سلكيّة وفرشاة
So what?! I don't like that tone of yours!
!ماذا؟ لا تروقني نبرتك
Yuko-san. After Kazue-san arrived, did you leave the classroom?
يوكو-سان، هل غادرتِ الفصل بعد وصول كازوي-سان؟
Yes, I went to the bathroom.
أجل، ذهبتُ لدورة المياه
I've figured it out.
اكتشفتُ الأمر
You killed her, Kazue-san!
!المجرم هو أنت يا كازوي-سان
Kazue-san did?!
!كازوي-سان؟
You can't be serious!
!لا يمكن
You stole the skewer while Yuko-san was in the bathroom!
سرقتِ السيخ بينما كانت !يوكو-سان في دورة المياه
You were able to accurately find and stab Uemori-san in the dark
تمكّنتِ من معرفة موقع أويموري-سان وطعنها في الظلام
because your eyes were used to the dark thanks to those dark glasses!
لأنّ عينيك معتادتان على الظلام بسبب !نظّاراتك المُظلمة هذه
Isn't that right?!
!أأنا مُخطئ؟
Quit joking around! I'm sensitive to light due to my age!
لا تمزح معي! أنا أعاني حساسيةً !من الضوء بسبب سنّي
That's why I wear these glasses!
!لذا أرتدي هذه النظّارات
Kazue-san, during class,
،كازوي-سان، أثناء الدرس
you left your bag at your feet instead of in the dining room.
تركتِ حقيبتك عند قدميك بدل غرفة الطعام
Why?
لمَ ذلك؟
Because it's more convenient that way!
!لأنّ ذلك أريح لي
Yes, for taking out the skewer!
!أريح في إخراج السيخ بسرعة
I don't have the skewer!
!السيخ ليس معي
Besides, how could I stab someone if it didn't have a handle?!
كما قد لا أستطيع الطعن به !بما أنّه لا يحمل مقبضاً
But you could make one.
لكن يمكنك صنعه
Using this brush of yours!
!باستعمال فرشاتك هذه
This will create a handle!
هكذا يصبح لديك مقبض
And the skewer in question is hidden in this notebook!
!والسيخ مخبّأٌ هنا
I-It's not there?! That's impossible!
!لـ-ليس هنا؟! مستحيل
The skewer is supposed to be under the rings!
!يُفترض أنّ السيخ داخل السلك
Hey. Is this the missing skewer?
انظر، أليس هذا السيخ المفقود؟
A splint?
تقويم؟
Oh, yeah! My mother-in-law did that!
صحيح، قامت حماتي بذلك
She asked if there was anything to use as a splint last night.
سألت إذا ما كان هناك شيء تستطيع استعماله للتقويم البارحة
It would seem the murder weapon wasn't a skewer.
يبدو أنّ سلاح الجريمة لم يكن السيخ
Yeah...
أجل
Honestly! Give me a break, will you?!
!يا إلهي! ارفقوا بي
Hello? This is Megure.
مرحباً؟ معك ميغوري
Got it.
فهمت
That was the hospital.
كان المشفى
Uemori-san's wound was 5 cm deep and under 1 mm in diameter.
كان جرح أويموري-سان بعمق 5 سم ويقلّ عن 1 مم في قطره
Under one millimeter?! Then that means...
...أقلّ من 1 مم؟! أيعني ذلك
The murder weapon wasn't a skewer or an ice pick. It was needle-like.
لم يكن سلاح الجريمة سيخاً أو كسّارة ثلج، بل شيئاً أشبه بالإبرة
Needle-like...
...أشبه بالإبرة
Oh! So it was you!
!فهمت! كان أنت
A nurse would be familiar with using syringes.
الممرضات معتادات على استعمال المحاقن
There must be some syringe needles less than 1 mm in diameter and over 5 cm in length!
لا بدّ من وجود محقنة يقلّ قطرها !عن 1 مم، ويزيد طولها على 5 سم
So what?!
!وما في ذلك؟
Now I got it!
!اكتشفتُ هذه المرّة
You killed her, Kaoru-san!
!المجرم هو أنت يا كاورو-سان
D-Don't be stupid! How am I the killer?!
!لا-لا تكن أحمق! لمَ أنا القاتلة؟
That eye patch isn't for a sty!
،ضمادة عينك هذه ليست لشحاذ
It was meant to keep one eye accustomed to the dark!
!بل لكي تعتاد عينك على الظلام
When the lights went out, you removed that eye patch
عندما انطفأت الأنوار، خلعتِ هذه الضمادة
and used your left eye to commit the crime!
!ونظرتِ بعينك اليسرى وحدها لارتكاب الجريمة
In-law strife was probably your motive!
!كان الدافع نزاعاً بين الحماة وزوجة الابن غالباً
Don't make these things up!
!لا تختلق هذه الأشياء
Then please remove your eye patch.
فلتخلعي ضمادة عينك لنا إذاً
That should be no problem, if you really have a sty.
يُفترض أنّه لا مشكلة إن كان مجرّد شحاذ حقّاً
Fine.
حسناً
Kaoru-san! How'd you get that black eye?!
!كاورو-سان! كيف أصابتك هذه الكدمة؟
My husband hit me.
ضربني زوجي
Then you wore the eye patch to hide that bruise?
استعملتِ هذه الضمادة لإخفاء الكدمة إذاً؟
Yes. That's right.
أجل، صحيح
Everyone here knows,
،الجميع هنا يعرفون
but my mother-in-law dotes over her son Tatsuhiko, my husband.
لكن حماتي كانت تدلّل ابنها، زوجي تاتسوهيكو
She was always, "Tatsuhiko this, Tatsuhiko that..."
كان ذكر اسمه على لسانها دوماً
He even hit me last night because I talked bad about her.
ضربني البارحة لأنّي تفوّهت بسوءٍ عنها
Where is Tatsuhiko-san now?
أين تاتسوهيكو-سان الآن؟
He left for Hawaii on a business trip this morning.
غادر إلى هاواي في رحلة عمل صباح اليوم
I wonder how he'll react when he finds out his mother's been killed.
أتساءل كيف ستكون ردّة فعله عندما يكتشف أنّ أمّه ماتت؟
I'd love to see it.
أتمنّى رؤيتها
Y-You still aren't cleared of suspicion! You can see out of that eye!
لـ-لم تزل الشبهات حولك بعد! يمكنك الرؤية !بعينك اليسرى تلك
But the weapon wasn't a syringe needle.
لكن لم يكن السلاح إبرة محقنة
There was almost no blood on Uemori-sensei's back.
فبالكاد كان هناك أيّ دم على ظهر أويموري سينسي
Blood would've followed the syringe needle up to the skin
كان الدم ليتبع إبرة المحقنة لسطح البشرة
after it broke through the capillaries!
!بعد تجاوزه للشعيرات الدمويّة
Why do you insist on making me the killer?
لمَ تصرّ على جعلي القاتلة؟
Just so you know, I'm not the only one with a motive for killing her.
ليكن في علمك، لستُ الوحيدة التي تمتلك دافعاً لقتلها
The other three have plenty of reason, too.
يملك الثلاثة الآخرون دوافعَ قويّة بدورهم
What?!
!ماذا؟
Kaoru-san! Stop saying nonsense!
!كاوري-سان! لا تتفوّهي بالهراء
Is it nonsense?
حقّاً؟
You've been friends with her for over thirty years,
،كنتِ صديقةً لها لما يفوق ثلاثين عاماً
but you surely hated her husband.
لكن لا بدّ أنّك كنتِ تبغضينها
After all, she stole your lover twenty-seven years ago and married him!
فقد سرقت حبيبك قبل 27 عاماً، وتزوّجته
You've stayed single ever since, and only came here
بقيتِ عازبةً مُذ آنذاك، وكنتِ تأتين هنا
so you could see your old lover, her husband and my father-in-law.
فقط كي تري حبيبك القديم، زوجها وحماي
He died last year of an illness, though.
لكنّه مات العام الفائت من مرض
I guess you must've really loved him to keep coming to this class.
لا بدّ أنّكِ أحببتِه بشدّة بما أنّك لا تزالين تأتين لهذا البيت
Oh! So that's why she...
...فهمت! لذا قالت آنذاك
He was such a nice, gentle man...
كان رجلاً لطيفاً وصالحاً
Nishitani-kun, I hear she was going to cut off your financial support.
نيشيتاني-كن، سمعت أنّ حماتي قرّرت قطع دعمها الماليّ لك
Because she found someone with more talent than you.
فقد وجدت شخصاً موهوباً أكثر منك
So you had to give up your dream of having your own restaurant.
لذا تحتّم عليك نسيان حلمك بفتح مطعمك الخاصّ
Is that true, Nishitani-kun?
أذلك صحيح يا نيشيتاني-كن؟
Yuko-san, you surely held a grudge because she stole your recipes.
يوكو-سان، كنتِ حاقدةً عليها بدورك لسرقتها وصفاتك
No! I didn't!
!البتّة! لم أحقد عليها
I saw it.
رأيتُك
I saw you crying while arguing with her.
رأيتُك تبكين وأنتِ تتجادلين معها
She coldly responded with, "If you don't like it, then surpass me."
ردّت عليكِ ببرودة آنذاك: "إذا كان الأمر "يغيظك، فعليكِ التفوّق عليّ
In other words, all four of you had reasons for killing Uemori-san.
أي أنّكم الأربعة كنتم تمتلكون دوافعَ لقتل أويموري-سان
Come to think of it...
...بالمناسبة
Nishitani-san, you massaged Uemori-sensei's shoulders.
قمتَ بتدليك كتفَي أويموري سينسي يا نيشيتاني-سان، أليس كذلك؟
Yes.
بلى
Meaning you must know about therapeutic points on the back.
مما يعني أنّك تعرف المواضع العلاجيّة على الظهر
I believe acupuncture needles are less than 1 mm in diameter.
قطر الإبر المستعملة في العلاج يقلّ عن 1 مم وفقما أذكر
But, Mori-san.
،لكن يا موري-سان
Yuko-san and I couldn't find her in the dark,
لم أستطع ويوكو-سان إيجادها في الظلام
and I've never touched an acupuncture needle in my life.
ولم يسبق لي أن لمست إبرة علاج في حياتي
Mori-kun, I've had acupuncture on occasion.
موري-كن، خضتُ علاج إبر بدوري
Those needles would be too thin.
وتلك الإبر رفيعةٌ جدّاً، فلا تنفع
They're so thin and weak that stabbing 5 cm in would be impossible.
إنّها رفيعةٌ وضعيفة بحيث يستحيل أن تطعن بعمق 5 سم
Too thin, huh?
رفيعة جدّاً إذاً؟
Wait a minute.
تمهل
Here's the blouse you asked me to mend.
هذه البلوزة التي طلبتِ منّي إصلاحها
A sewing set. You're the only one with one, correct?
عدّة خياطة، أنتِ الوحيدة التي تحمل واحدةً بين الأربعة، صحيح؟
What difference does that make?
وما في ذلك؟
5 cm in length. Under 1 mm in width.
الطول 5 سم، والقطر يقلّ عن 1 مم
Matches the murder weapon perfectly!
!يطابق سلاح الجريمة تماماً
Get real! How would you pull it out if you stuck it all the way in?!
كفّ عن هذا! كيف تُخرجها إذا !طعنت بها بالكامل؟
Oh, right.
معكِ حقّ
Sheesh...
...يا إلهي
Besides, people are surprisingly tough-skinned,
بالأصل، الناس قُساة البشرة بخلاف ما تتوقّعه
and there's no way to grip a sewing needle for stabbing anyway.
فيستحيل أن تستطيع الطعن بإبرة بلا ممسك
It's true that a sewing needle fits the murder weapon perfectly.
من الصحيح أنّ إبرة الخياطة أكثر ما يلائم سلاح الجريمة
But a 5 cm stab wound wouldn't be possible.
لكن الطعن بعمق 5 سم أمرٌ مستحيل
Wait! A sewing needle...
انتظر! إبرة خياطة؟
Yeah! With that, you could stab someone!
!أجل! يمكنك الطعن باستعمال تلك
And, being able to find Uemori-sensei in the dark...
...ولإيجاد أويموري سينسي في الظلام
It would be easy with that, and not immediately obvious!
!سيكون الأمر سهلاً باستعمال ذلك، ولن يبدو جليّاً
So that's why that person made that mistake...
...لذا ارتكب ذلك الشخص ذاك الخطأ آنذاك
This is the men's room window,
،هذه نافذة حمّام الفتيان
so it should be around here somewhere.
فيُفترض أنّها في هذه الأرجاء
Here it is! Which means it contains...
...ها هي! مما يعني أنّ محتواها
Kazue-san.
كازوي-سان
It's possible that a sewing needle was the murder weapon,
هنالك احتمال بأنّ إبرة الخياطة كانت سلاح الجريمة
so we'll have to run a test for blood on them.
لذا علينا إجراء فحص دمّ لها
Do as you like. There's no point, though.
افعل ما يحلو لك، فلا جدوى من الأمر
It's also possible to hide a needle in your clothes,
وهنالك احتمال بإخفاء أحدكم للإبرة في ثيابه
so we'll need to conduct body searches.
لذا علينا إجراء تفتيش بدنيّ لكم
Eh?! Even that?!
!ماذا؟ ستفعلون ذلك حتّى؟
We have our rights!
!لدينا حقوقنا
I found it! This is it!
!وجدتُها! ها هي
So that person really is the killer!
!المجرم كان ذاك الشخص بالفعل إذاً
I know who did it. Now for the murder weapon.
عرفتُ هويّة الفاعل، بقي سلاح الجريمة
If I were going to hide that weapon...
...لو كنتُ سأخفيه
Ah! Inside there!
!فهمت، في داخله
That's quite a clever hiding place!
!يا للمخبأ الماكر
Inspector Megure.
مفتّش ميغوري
Oh, how'd it go?
ما النتيجة؟
No blood was detected on anything in the sewing set.
لم نجد أيّ دم على الأدوات في عدّة الخياطة
I see. Thank you.
فهمت، شكراً لكم
Inspector!
حضرة المفتّش
Did the body search turn up anything, Takagi-kun?
كيف مضى التفتيش البدنيّ يا تاكاغي-كن؟
Nishitani-san doesn't have a needle on him.
لم يكن بحوزة نيشيتاني-سان أيّة إبر
And the women?
والنساء؟
Nothing turned up.
لم أجد شيئاً
Inspector.
حضرة المفتّش
Could you let Yuko-san and me go?
هلّا سمحتِ لي ويوكو-سان بالمغادرة؟
As I mentioned before, neither of us could've found her in the dark.
كما ذكرتُ سابقاً، لم نكن نستطيع إيجاد المعلّمة في الظلام
That's true...
...صحيح
Inspector, you must not let those two go yet.
حضرة المفتّش، لا يمكنك السماح لهما بعد بالمغادرة
Huh? Why not, Mori-kun?
ماذا؟ لمَ ذلك يا موري-كن؟
Because I know who the killer is.
لأنّي عرفت هويّة القاتل
Say what?!
!ماذا؟
You do, Dad?!
!حقّاً يا أبي؟
W-Who's the killer?!
!مـ-من هو القاتل؟
The one who murdered Uemori Michi-san...
...من قتل أويموري ميتشي-سان
...was you, Nishitani-san!
!كان أنت يا نيشيتاني-سان
What?!
!ماذا؟
Mori-san, weren't you listening just now?
موري-سان، ألم تكن تسمع كلامي؟
Yuko-san and I couldn't have--
...لم أستطع ويوكو-سان
There was a way to find Uemori-san, even in the darkness.
توجد طريقة لإيجاد أويموري-سان حتّى بالظلام
By wearing special contact lenses in advance.
وذلك بارتداء عدسات لاصقة خاصّة سلفاً
Contact lenses?
عدسات لاصقة؟
Yes. He wore black, sunglass-like contact lenses.
أجل، ارتدى عدسات لاصقة سوداء شبيهة بالنظّارات الشمسيّة
When he first entered the classroom, he didn't have them in.
عندما دخل هذا الفصل بدايةً، لم يكن يضعها
Nor when he snuck through the back entrance before then.
ولا عندما تسلّل عبر الباب الخلفيّ قبلها
This is because they would've been inconvenient
هذا لأنّها كانت ستعيقه عندما
when setting up the ice trick in the electrical room.
ينصب حيلة القالب الجليديّ في غرفة المفاتيح
He put the contacts in about ten minutes before class began,
ارتدى العدسات قبل 10 دقائق تقريباً من بدء الدرس
in the bathroom.
في دورة المياه
Eh?! Then that's why he--?
...ماذا؟ لذا وقتها
Yes. That's why when he ran into you in the hallway...
...أجل، لذا عندما التقاكِ في الرواق
Ran-san! Sorry! My mistake! You look alike!
!ران-سان! آسف! تبدوان متشابهتين فخلطت بينكما
The hallway here is rather dark,
،الرواق هنا خافت الإضاءة
so he couldn't differentiate between you and Yuko-san.
فلم يستطع التمييز بينك ويوكو-سان
But he wasn't clumsier than usual!
لكن لم تختلف مهاراته بيديه عن المعتاد
That's because he's skilled and the classroom was quite bright.
،هذا لأنّه كان بارعاً بالأصل وغرفة الفصل مُنارة بما يكفي
But do such convenient contact lenses actually exist?
لكن أتوجد عدسات لاصقة بتلك الأريحيّة حقّاً؟
No, not normally.
كلا، ليس عادةً
In Japan, contact lenses are pharmaceutical products,
في اليابان، العدسات اللاصقة منتجات صيدليّة
Visible Light Transmission
نقل الضوء المرئيّ
so there's a specific standard for visible light transmission,
،"فيُفرض عليها "نسبة نقل الضوء المرئيّ أي معيار محدّد لمرور الضوء
so contact lenses as dark as sunglasses can't be sold.
فلا يمكن بيع العدسات اللاصقة المُظلمة مثل النظّارات الشمسية
The color contacts that were recently put on the market
العدسات اللاصقة الملوّنة التي دخلت السوق مؤخراً
only have color around the lens; the middle is still transparent.
،تحمل اللون حول العدسات فقط ويبقى المنتصف شفّافاً
But lenses with color in any location can be specially ordered
لكن يمكن طلب عدسات ملوّنة في أيّ موضع بشكلٍ خاص
for use in things like TV dramas and commercials.
للاستعمال في الدراما التلفزيّة والإعلانات
So they're not absolutely impossible to obtain.
لذا الحصول عليها ليس مستحيلاً
In any event, Nishitani-san let his eyes grow accustomed to the dark,
أيّاً يكن، عوّد نيشيتاني-سان ،عينيه بتلك العدسات
and the instant the lights went out, he quickly removed the contacts,
ولحظة انقطاع التيّار، خلعها فوراً
opened the sliding door, approached Uemori-san,
وفتح الباب المزلاجيّ واقترب من أويموري-سان
and stabbed her in the back!
!وطعن ظهرها
Mori-kun! What was the murder weapon?!
!موري-كن! ما كان سلاح الجريمة؟
I believe the weapon was indeed a sewing needle.
أعتقد أنّ سلاح الجريمة كان إبرة خياطة
A sewing needle?
إبرة خياطة؟
But you said yourself it wouldn't be easy to stab 5 cm with one,
لكنّك قلت قبل قليل أنّ الطعن ،بعمق 5 سم بها ليس سهلاً
and it might get stuck if you're not careful!
!وقد تعلق إذا لم تتوخَّ الحذر
A thimble and some thread solve those problems.
يمكن حلّ تلك المشاكل بكشتبان وخيط
A thimble and thread?
كشتبان وخيط؟
A thimble? You mean the ring that's used when doing needlework?
كشتبان؟ أتقصد الخاتم الذي يُرتدى عند الخياط اليدويّة؟
That's right. Have a look at Nishitani-san's right index finger.
صحيح، فلتنظروا لسبّابة نيشيتاني-سان اليمنى من فضلكم
He used the ring as a thimble?!
!استعمل الخاتم كشتباناً؟
Yes. He put a thread through the needle, and...
...صحيح، مرّر خيطاً بالإبرة، ثمّ
But I believe he burned the thread using his stove to be rid of it.
لكنّي أظنّه حرق الخيط الذي استعمله آنذاك بموقد الفرن غالباً
Hold on! That means the evidence is--!
...مهلك، هذا يعني أنّ الدليل
Fear not, Inspector.
لا تقلق حضرة المفتّش
Conan!
!كونان
I found this behind the bathrooms!
وجدتُ هذه في الجانب الخلفيّ لدورة المياه
A contact lens case?
حافظة عدسات لاصقة؟
Yeah!
أجل
Nishitani-san threw it out the bathroom window after putting 'em in!
ألقاها نيشيتاني-سان من نافذة الحمّام بعدما ارتداها
And I found this one inside his cooking bowl!
كما وجدتُ هذا الفرد داخل !وعاء طهو نيشيتاني-سان
A contact lens...
عدسة لاصقة؟
Takagi-kun!
!تاكاغي-كن
Right!
!حاضر
Inspector! I found the other lens!
!حضرة المفتّش! وجدتُ العدسة الأخرى
Nishitani-san. Think you can you explain this for us?
نيشيتاني-سان، هلّا شرحت لنا ما يعنيه هذا؟
Is something wrong with wearing sunglass-like contacts?
أهناك خطبٌ ما بارتداء عدسات لاصقة شبيهة بالنظّارات الشمسيّة؟
You should find the weapon before accusing someone of murder!
فلتجدوا سلاح الجريمة قبل توجيه !تهمة القتل لشخص
But the weapon is in your belongings.
لكنّ سلاح الجريمة بين ممتلكاتك
Inside your ballpoint pen.
داخل قلم حبرك
Here it is!
!ها هو
Nishitani-san! Are you still going to make excuses?
!نيشيتاني-سان! لا تزال تنوي التهرّب؟
I thought it was a great hiding place, too...
...ظننتُه كان مخبأً رائعاً
I lose, Mori-san. You truly are a great detective.
،أعترف بخسارتي يا موري-سان كما يُتوقع من المتحرّي العظيم
I got the contacts when I went to Europe last month for training.
حصلتُ على العدسات اللاصقة عندما ذهبتُ لأوروبا الشهر الفائت للتمرين
I paid someone at a manufacturer to make them.
دفعتُ لأحد العاملين في شركة صانعة ليصنعها لي
I figured Japanese contacts could've been traced.
فقد ارتأيتُ أنّ العدسات اللاصقة اليابانيّة ستكون سهلة التعقّب
And your motive?
ودافعك؟
Was it because she was cutting off your financial support?
ألأنّها قطعت دعمها الماليّ لك حقّاً؟
There's that, but I felt bad that Yuko-san's recipes were being stolen.
ذلك جزء، لكنّي شعرتُ بالأسف على يوكو-سان بعدما سُرقت وصفاتها
So I wanted to enact my plan the night before her best-seller party.
لذا أردتُ تنفيذ خطّتي الليلة السابقة لحفلة كتابها الأكثر مبيعاً
Yuko-san. You might not have realized it, but I've always...
...يوكو-سان، ربما لم تلحظي، لكنّي لطالما كنت
I knew how you felt.
عرفتُ مشاعرك
But I never wanted you to do this.
لكنّي لم أردك أن تُقدم على هذا البتّة
My goal was to improve myself
كان هدفي هو تطوير نفسي
and create perfect recipes that she couldn't help with...
وصنع وصفات مثالية لا تستطيع المعلّمة المساعدة فيها
Nishitani-san. Your actions weren't based on love.
نيشيتاني-سان، لم يكن الحُب المحرّض لأفعالك
They were nothing but criminal actions resulting from selfishness!
كانت مجرّد فعلة إجراميّة نبعت من أنانيّتك البحتة
A different cooking classroom?
ماذا؟ فصل طهو آخر؟
Yeah!
أجل
After what happened to Uemori-sensei,
،بعدما حلّ بأويموري سينسي
Sonoko decided to go to a different cooking classroom.
قرّرت سونوكو الذهاب لفصل طهو دراسيّ آخر
She asked if I wanted to go, too!
!وسألتني إذا ما كنت أريد مرافقتها
French cooking again?
طهو فرنسيّ مُجدداً؟
Yeah, that's right!
!أجل، صحيح
So, can I enroll, Dad? It costs the same as Uemori-sensei's place!
يمكنني الذهاب يا أبي، صحيح؟ فتكلفته نفس تكلفة فصل أويموري سينسي
The same? How much is that?
نفسها؟ كم بالضبط؟
10,000 yen for one class a month.
عشرة آلاف ينّ للفصل الواحد شهرياً
10,000 yen for one class?!
!عشرة آلاف ينّ لفصلٍ واحد؟
These sardines are great! Japanese people love Japanese food!
هذا السردين لذيذٌ حقّاً! لا غنى لليابانيّين !عن الأكل اليابانيّ حقّاً
I guess you should forget about the cooking classroom...
يبدو أنّك عليكِ نسيان فكرة فصل الطهو
It seems so.
ذلك ما يبدو
Yes, yes!
!أجل، أجل
I guess I won't be eating any of Ran's French cooking for awhile.
لن نأكل طهو ران الفرنسيّ لفترة وفقما يبدو
The anatomy model?
نموذج التشريح؟
I saw it running super-fast through the hallway four nights ago!
!كان يركض قبل أربع ليال في الرواق! وبسرعةٍ فائقة
Look! That white fog on the glass!
انظري! هذه البقعة الضبابيّة !البيضاء على الزجاج
It's proof that someone was pressed against the window, looking out!
!إنّها دليلٌ على التصاق أحدهم بالنافذة، واستراقه النظر
Blood!
!دم
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Nurse's office.
غرفة تشريح
Next episode takes place at a school at night.
مسرح الحلقة القادمة !هو مدرسة ليلاً
What do they teach you at that kind of school?
ما الذي تعلّمه تلك المدرسة؟
That's not what that means.
ليس بذاك المعنى